# SEDAT SERCAN CENGIZ



+90 0534 254 1785 sercancng@gmail.com Kecioren / ANKARA

#### **PROFILE**

Baskent Universities computer engineering department student, who strong in human relations, programmed and planned in his studies and sees software development as an entertainment rather than seeing it as a job. With more than 3 years of experience in Java and Android application development, he is skilled in this field and prone to teamwork. Developing their own projects at every opportunity. He has 6 months of research and development experience in machine learning and artificial intelligence. I have been working on web-based application development, designing websites and at the Front-End for a year. He is currently engaged in research and development activities on the autonomous drone movement in the field of artificial intelligence.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Intern Engineer, Turkish Aerospace Industries, Ankara - 2019 - Current Designing and developing GUI for MMU project.

## Intern, HAVELSAN A.S, Ankara - 2019

Preparing XML for working in TeamCity program, XML Builder preparation to make it easier to prepare XML from available data, Designing and developing a GUI for the prepared XML Builder, Studies on Docker and AWX.

# Intern Engineer, Turkish Aerospace Industries, Ankara - 2018 - 2019

Preparation of license management system and preparation of a website suitable for this system, Studies on time synchronization between servers.

# Intern, ATAR Labs Bilisim A.S, Ankara - 2018

Testing the previously prepared Scripts on the system, Preparing new scripts to work on ATAR, Preparation of job tracking system between jobs & users.

## **EDUCATION**

Baskent University, Ankara - 2015 - Current

GPA: 3.49 / 4.00

Alparslan Anatolian High School, Ankara - 2011 - 2015

# **SKILLS**

C, C++, C#, Java, Kotlin, Python, Perl, SQL, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

# **FOREIGN LANGUAGES**

English (Upper-Intermediate), Turkish (Native Language) PROJECTS

### **PROJECTS**

#### **Android**

- MarketApp: Showing the products in the system to the user, listing similar products and adding selected products to the basket
- **UlasBana**: Visual design, interface development, earning points and saving the score in the database
- **Cliya**: Development of the system that enables doctors to enter the diseases database, informing the user if there is an epidemic in the region where it is located
- Where Is My Gift: A mobile game like Flappy Bird
- A social media app study like Onedio tests
- Firebase application that encrypts end-to-end using AES for internal communications
- Information application about music groups

#### Java

- Animal information and tracking system for pet-shops
- · Game bot systems prepared with Selenium

### **Kotlin**

• Designing and developing a GUI to make it easier to prepare XML

### C#

- Stack of Shape: Mobile game prepared with Unity 3D
- Tap Picture: Mobile game prepared with Unity 3D
- Simulation environment for drone artificial intelligence with Unity 3D

### **DEGREE, SCHOLARSHIP AND CERTIFICATES**

- OSYM 50% Education Scholarship
- METU Hackaton 2019, Participant
- Iste Baskent 2018, Participant
- E-GameShow Redbull-GboxVR 2017, Organization Team
- Iste Baskent 2017, Organization Team

# **REFERENCES**

- Emre SÜMER, Baskent University, Deputy Head of Computer Engineering Department, 0312 246 6666 / 1305
- Mehmet Bugra BILMEZ, Kale Yazılım, Software Specialist, 0 (533) 542 93 07
- Serkan KUCUK, Innova Bilisim Cozumleri A.S, Application Development Consultant, 0 (533) 706 66 89
- Sena Nur GOREN, TUBITAK Bilgem Iltaren, Researcher, 0 (538) 611 74 85
- Ahmet DEDE, HAVELSAN, DevOps Engineer, 0 (506) 332 84 43